Heroes come in all shapes and sizes... even rectangles.
The Boxtrolls is a animation, comedy, family film directed by Graham Annable.
An orphaned boy raised by underground creatures called Boxtrolls comes up from the sewers and out of
his box to save his family and the town from the evil exterminator, Archibald Snatcher.
Snatcher (voice), played by Ben Kingsley.
Eggs (voice), played by Isaac Hempstead Wright.
Winnie Portley-Rind (voice), played by Elle Fanning.
Fish / Wheels / Bucket (voice), played by Dee Bradley Baker.
Lady Cynthia Portley-Rind (voice), played by Toni Collette.
Lord Portley-Rind (voice), played by Jared Harris.
The Boxtrolls is a 2014 American stop motion animated fantasy comedy
film loosely based on the 2005 novel Here Be Monsters!.
Directed by Graham Annable and Anthony Stacchi, and produced by Laika, it features the voices of Ben Kingsley, Isaac Hempstead Wright, Elle
Fanning, Dee Bradley Baker, Steve Blum, Toni Collette, Jared Harris, Nick Frost, Richard Ayoade, Tracy Morgan, and Simon Pegg.
Set in the fictional European country of Norvenia in the late 19th century, the film tells the story of Eggs, a human boy
raised by trash-collecting trolls, known as "Boxtrolls", as he attempts to save them from a pest exterminator.
In 2008, Laika unveiled a slate of projects in development, including an animated
feature film adaptation of the Alan Snow novel Here Be Monsters!.
While the animation technique was not yet decided
upon, Stacchi was set to direct the film.
Originally focused on all five species of creatures found in the original book, producer
Travis Knight noted that the script ultimately was hollow with all the monsters.
As the result, the team ended up focusing on the Boxtrolls as Knight thought there was
something that was really compelling about that group of characters.
Dario Marianelli composed the film's musical score.
The film was released in the United States on September 26, 2014, by Focus Features, and
received generally positive reviews from critics, who praised the humor and animation.
It earned $108 million on a $60 million budget and was nominated for Best
Animated Film at the Academy Awards, the Golden Globes and the BAFTAs.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, parent child
relationship, stop motion, unlikely friendship, duringcreditsstinger.
The tone is lighthearted.